Levi and the Scouts clashed with Kenny's squad,
charging straight into their defense.
All to reach and rescue Eren and Historia.
However...
Fall back to the final defensive post!
Time to regroup!
I'm praying, Historia.
For God to lead and guide humanity!
God, my ass!
You're just giving yourself an out
and manipulating other people!
I've had it! I won't let you kill me!
That's the spirit!
This is gettin' good!
You escape from here.
I'll destroy everything else!
Father...
Uri...
Frieda...
Wait for me...
...now...
It's gotta be a way through
if it's all plugged up.
Shit.
If only we had some gunpowder left...
We cannot let them through!
As long as we hold here, we're good!
That's...
A Titan transformed?
Eren!
Here it comes! Hang on tight!
Th-This place is gonna collapse!
Captain!
The hole!
Armin! Moblit! Take Hange
and get the hell out of here!
Rod Reiss!
You bastard!
Forget it, Historia!
Since that Titan's from the Reiss family,
just let him come and eat me!
Get out of here!
Hell no!
Why won't you listen?!
I might be humanity's enemy, but I'm your ally!
I can't be a good girl,
and I don't wanna be God either!
But...
When I see people crying to themselves,
saying they're not needed...
...I wanna tell those people
that's just not true!
No matter who! No matter where!
I'll come to their rescue!
Historia!
You okay?
Mikasa!
Give me the keys!
Captain? You guys...
Conny, hurry!
Forget about me!
Captain! Hurry and escape!
Shut up already, you topless wimp!
It's not just a Titan!
There're dudes with guns coming for us!
He's loose!
I think...
That's way bigger than
the Colossal Titan, isn't it?
The ceiling...? Look out!
Get back!
Hey, hey, Rod! Ya done goofed up big time!
You thought ya knew Titans
more than the rest of us!
Now I know you didn't, ya dumb shit!
Captain Ackermann!
Idiots! Get away!
Shit! There's no way out!
Why?
Wasn't he going to eat me?
Should I transform?
No... My Titan can't withstand all this...
I'm sorry, everyone...
I've been nothing but useless...
Ever since the very beginning,
I was never the hope of humanity...
Armor?
What's this? Think you're some tragic hero?
When have you ever accomplished
anything by your strength alone?
What a weakling.
We've been through much worse than this.
Not that I wanna get used to it!
Still, it's going to suck trying
to navigate through all that.
I'll take Eren.
We can't go nice and slow for you,
so hold on for your life.
Right.
It's useless. We can't escape.
So do nothing?
You wanna sit here and hold hands
till we're crushed or burn to death?
Because we're enemies of humanity?
You know, I hate doing this
to you every time, but...
Eren.
You've gotta make the choice.
I'll go with you!
Eren!
I'm sorry...
Since it's the end, just this once...
I want you to let me...
Let me believe in myself!
What... the...?
Everyone! Get underneath Eren!
Caven!
The chapel!
Not good!
Let's try to run!
Section Commander! Are you okay?!
Yeah...
What in the world happened?
What the hell is that?
If it's that big this far away...
It's gotta be twice as big
as the Colossal Titan.
The wall won't stand a chance...
Commander?
Advance!
Eren!
"Titan Hardening" "An ability used by the Armored
Titan and so forth, for a Titan to harden their body.
While in hiding, Eren Jaeger conducted experiments
to replicate this ability in order to plug Wall Maria."
That's what I call hardening.
Even after cutting you away,
the Titan hasn't disappeared.
Pretty impressive, yeah?
That bottle...
Oh, yeah! Right before I turned into
a Titan, I drank that "Armor" bottle...
Yeah.
You couldn't do it at all before now,
but you used the hardening power.
And saved all of us.
In the blink of an eye,
you devised and built all this.
Yeah, the construction looks shoddy, but...
I bet that's how the walls were made, too.
In other words...
It's possible for us to plug
that hole in Wall Maria now.
A lot of enemies and allies
have died on the way,
and getting this far hasn't been pretty,
but for as ugly as it's been,
look at the position we're in now.
Retaking Wall Maria...
Once we do that,
we can investigate my basement.
But, my dad was actually...
Captain!
We've secured an exit!
Armin's safe!
Hange and Moblit, too!
Well done.
Eren!
You okay?
We're all safe, thanks to you!
But to be perfectly honest, when you ran
off prancing while crying like a baby...
...I thought we were doomed!
"It's over, over! Get it together, nincompoop!
Quit bawling like a snotty-nosed brat!"
is what I thought.
Hey...
Let's go.
We're going after that big-ass Titan.
Eren!
It's no use! Stay back! We'll get burnt!
Commander, we can't stop it!
It's like an Abnormal and doesn't care about us!
Enough! Fall back!
All that matters for now is to find
out the direction it's heading.
Commander Erwin! It's Squad Levi!
Eren and Historia are with them!
They succeeded!
Erwin.
Everyone all right?
Hange's our only casualty.
Seems like nothing too serious.
Well done, everyone.
I've got a whole slew of things
to report, but first...
What's that Titan?
It's Rod Reiss.
I think we'll need your call on this, Commander.
Regardless, we don't have time
to stand here and chat.
Return to Wall Sina.
You're going to let that big ass
crawl right up to the wall?
To Orvud District, actually.
That's most likely where it's headed.
Let's put this all together...
Basically, Rod Reiss was after the Founding
Titan, the Titan power inside Eren.
However, unless it's in someone with Reiss
blood, you won't get its true potential.
Though, even if a Reiss obtains
the Founding Titan's power,
they're controlled by the First King's will and
refuse to liberate humanity from the Titans.
Eh? Well, isn't that interesting...
According to the First King, this is true peace?
Now that's a weird way to look at it.
In other words... we still have an option.
If that Titan eats me,
Rod Reiss will return to a human.
Which means it's still possible
to have a true Founding Titan.
You can't...
Seems that way.
We could capture Rod Reiss
once he becomes a human.
Undo the First King's brainwashing.
If we could do that, it might open
a path to save humanity.
Plus, Eren...
Are you saying you're fully
prepared to let that happen?
I am.
Eren, you can't...
You're forgetting our other option.
First of all, the current plan is full of flaws.
One, there's no proof that you can
undo Rod Reiss' brainwashing.
No matter how you restrain him,
if he alters humanity's memories, it's over.
Basically, there's too many factors about
the Founding Titan that we just don't know.
True...
Even if Rod Reiss eats Eren, we have
no guarantee that he'll return to normal.
Mmm.
On the other hand, all we've ever
known is destructive pacifists.
But as it stands, the Founding Titan
was taken from them.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime chance for humanity.
Yes...
Your father was trying to save us
and humanity from the First King.
He stole the Founding Titan from my sister...
...murdered all of the Reiss children...
...because he had no other choice.
If you want to save Mikasa,
Armin, and everyone else...
...you must learn to control this ability!
Dad...
That's right!
The Dr. Jaeger I know wouldn't do
something like that for no reason at all.
Right. Even without having Reiss blood,
there must be a way to save humanity.
That's why he left you the key to the basement.
What basement?
Oh, that whole thing?
You mean it's actually important?
Uh, yeah...
We've finally got a way to plug up the wall.
The way I see it, there's only one choice.
That makes life a little easier.
If it means anything, I agree with that choice.
Though, are you sure about this, Historia?
We can't exactly have a Titan like that
wandering around inside the walls.
One that big, we can't restrain.
Meaning...
We'll have to kill your father
and there's no way around it.
Eren.
I'm sorry.
Eh?
Underneath the Reiss chapel...
...I really considered becoming
a Titan and killing you.
What's more, not even to save humanity...
Only because I wanted to believe my father.
I didn't want my father to hate me...
But now, it's time to say goodbye.
Please gather your squad in the hall.
The strategy meeting is about to begin.
All right.
Historia. Forgot to tell you...
We need you to do something.
Yes?
Erwin's orders.
When this battle is over, since you're
the true successor to the throne...
...become the Queen.
Eh?
Huh?
Q-Queen?! Historia?!
The coup d'état was successful, but the people
won't follow a regiment sitting at the top.
What we need is a story to spread.
That a true heir retook
the crown from the fake.
I...
Um, Captain?
I'm sure you heard what
Historia said earlier, but...
Well, uh...
By leaving her father, she finally broke free
from that burden, I guess you could say...
And yet, again...
What?
If you have something to say, say it.
Uh, um...
I-In other words...
Conny's trying to say...
Historia broke free from the Reiss
family and has finally found herself.
And now you're forcing her
into another role? Isn't that...?
Isn't that... not fair to her?
All right.
Eh?
My next duty is to be Queen, right?
Understood.
Historia...
Thanks for your concern.
But whether or not it's forced on me
is up to me to decide, I think.
However...
Captain, I do have one condition.
Hmm?
Since my fate is my own,
I want to lay it all on the line.
When you're Queen,
you can punch that runt in the face.
We've determined the location
of Rod Reiss' Titan.
It's southwest, approaching Orvud.
At this rate, it should reach
Orvud District by dawn.
Understood.
Commander Erwin, we'd all
like to hear what your plan is.
How do you intend to evacuate
the citizens in time?
We won't evacuate.
Wh-What?
We'll have the citizens remain in
Orvud District just as they are.
Uh...
Are you insane?
At Orvud District, Eren and the others
face off against Rod Reiss' Titan.
Meanwhile, Historia is determined
to decide her own fate.
Next episode: "Ruler of the Walls."